<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>JKR</title>
 <link href="https://jaredrichard.co.uk/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://jaredrichard.co.uk/"/>
 <updated>2021-03-18T01:24:12+00:00</updated>
 <id>https://jaredrichard.co.uk</id>
 <author>
   <name>Jared Richard</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>The Quiet Soldier</title>
   <link href="https://jaredrichard.co.uk/book-reviews/2021/03/16/quiet-soldier/"/>
   <updated>2021-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://jaredrichard.co.uk/book-reviews/2021/03/16/quiet-soldier</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An honest and intriguing description of selection for 21 SAS (Special Air Service) - a Special Forces branch of the UK military.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/quiet-soldier-cover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive-book&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book describes a process that lasts well over a year, first beginning with increasingly difficult treks across hills in the Brecon Beacons. Then moves onto TQ - &lt;em&gt;tactical questioning&lt;/em&gt; (i.e. interrogation), and then ‘continuation’ phase for another few months. On a standard selection round, 200+ men will start, around 10 will finish. Here, Adam Ballinger narrates his own successful experience back in the 1980s. (Interesting point: Adam and several other of the remaining 10 were were previous oxbridge graduates (including a physics student - Avery) and, according to Avery, ‘the reason the SAS badge is a mixture of light and dark blue is because there were so many Oxbridge graduates in the original regiment’).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summary: thoroughly enjoyed this book and would be interested in learning more about military life and special forces in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Quotes &amp;amp; Passages:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘For a young man who wants to enjoy himself, to spend a few years agreeably in military companionship … the British cavalry will be suited … To the youth who means to make himself a professional soldier, an expert in war, a specialist in practical tactics, who desires a hard life of adventure and a true comradeship in arms, I would recommend the choice of some regiment on the frontier.’&lt;/em&gt; - Winston Churchill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘It is not good to be too free. It is not good to have all one needs.’&lt;/em&gt; - Pascal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘It is not in man’s nature to always go in one direction; it has its ups and downs.’&lt;/em&gt; - Pascal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Don’t get too despondent,’ he said, looking downcast. ‘We all improve with time. In this regiment you’ve got to shoot a fly off a dog’s bollocks at four hundred yards.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘A tattoo is a mine of information. A man with a tattoo is a walking encyclopedia.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Service life in this way teaches man to live largely on little.’&lt;/em&gt; - T. E. Lawrence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Some of you will know Wood. He was trying to join Two Squadron. He’s just been dropped from this course. He had a criminal record. It wouldn’t matter, lads, but he said he didn’t. That’s why we ask you on attestation. It catches up with you eventually. You’ve got to tell the truth, lads. This regiment does not tolerate liars. When you come back from an exercise we’ve got to be able to rely on your word. People’s lives may depend on it.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Well done, lads,’ the Colonel said. ‘It’s hard to get into this regiment. But as your OC’s already told you, it’s even harder to stay in it. But well done – well done. ‘I’ve done some statistics and the results will interest you. Thirty per cent of you will leave within three years. One of you will go on to command a squadron and one of you will disgrace himself, and be dismissed from the regiment, within the first year.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Finding the right men,’ said Falstaff, ‘is like looking for diamonds. During Selection we knock away the bad rock until a rough diamond is found. Camp is a cutting process when we chip off the bad edges. Continuation is the polish. It’s our job to present clean diamonds to the regiment.’ ‘Can you spot the diamonds, in the rock, before the course begins?’ I asked. ‘Yes, I can,’ said Falstaff, his eyes twinkling. ‘It’s all in the eyes, and the mind. You remember having your photograph taken at the beginning of the course?’ ‘On attestation?’‘Yes. We put them all together on a big sheet of cardboard. I’ve got a black pen and we cross out every face that will fail. Ninety-five per cent of the time we’re right. It’s interesting to see them fall. Sometimes we put money on it. I can even tell when some of them will go. You can look at a man and say, “He’ll fail on weekend four, he’ll fail on Long Drag and he’ll fail on TQ.” You escaped the black pen, but Sampson is a surprise. We thought he’d fail. Most muscle men do.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Are you, then, so easily turned from your design? Did you not call this a glorious expedition? And wherefore was it glorious? Not because the way was smooth and placid as a southern sea, but because it was full of dangers and terror, because at every new incident your fortitude was to be called forth and your courage exhibited, because danger and death surrounded it, and these you were to brave and overcome. For this it was glorious, for this it was an honourable undertaking … Oh! Be men, or be more than men. Be steady to your purposes and firm as rock.’&lt;/em&gt; - Mary Shelley&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;New words:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;indefatigable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;equipoise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;assiduously&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;kip&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reveille&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lackadaisical&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sidled&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;antagonize&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;frogmarching&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;copious&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;karabiners&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;jubilant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;jovial&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;laconically&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pacifist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;desultorily&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;transiently&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;melt-water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sardonically&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bisecting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tantamount&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;fissure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;haphazard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unwittingly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;desultorily&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rabble&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;benevolent&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;uncanny&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wistfully&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Interstellar and The Information Paradox</title>
   <link href="https://jaredrichard.co.uk/physics/2021/03/11/physics-presentations/"/>
   <updated>2021-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://jaredrichard.co.uk/physics/2021/03/11/physics-presentations</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My Physics presentation in 2nd year, which was awarded First Prize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Interstellar’ and The Information Paradox&lt;/em&gt;, delivered to my fellow students and tutors as part of the 2nd Year Physics Presentations (a requirement in the Oxford Physics degree course), was greatly received and I was thankfully awarded First Prize for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iPsFOTikhJc&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk is an exploration into Christopher Nolan’s 2015 blockbuster &lt;em&gt;Interstellar&lt;/em&gt;, but more importantly the questions it throws up about modern physics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the film we see reference to information being extracted from a black hole. This is actually quite a famous paradox in Physics, namely ‘The Information Paradox’ and was birthed from Stephen Hawking’s revolutionary ideas about Black Holes and Quantum Mechanics in 1974.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He showed that black holes ‘evaporate’ and shrink over time down to nothing. The problem lies in the fact nothing can leave a black hole once it has entered, so if an object fell in, the black hole shrinks and disappears, then the information of the object would be lost?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wouldn’t be problem, apart from the fact that one of the most fundamental tenets in quantum physics, and physics in general, is that information can never be destroyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A potential solution was presented by Leonard Susskind and Gerard T’Hooft called ‘Black Hole Complementarity’ in which they say the inside and the outside of a black hole are 2 completely different situations, so we can treat them separately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For observer A that falls into the black hole, they take their information with them, never to return (continuously falling down to the singularity at the center, maybe eventually leaving this simulation we live in). For observer B, a different observer who watches on from far away, they never see observer A truly enter, they see them “freeze” at the surface due to time dilation and their information is then spread over the surface and later reradiated back out as Hawking Radiation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Top 150 Future Leaders - Magazine Feature</title>
   <link href="https://jaredrichard.co.uk/general/2021/02/01/future-leaders-magazine/"/>
   <updated>2021-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://jaredrichard.co.uk/general/2021/02/01/future-leaders-magazine</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Selected to be featured in the 2020/21 edition of &lt;em&gt;Future Leaders Magazine&lt;/em&gt;: an annual publication celebrating the top 150 black university students in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/future-leaders1.png&quot; alt=&quot;future leader pic 1&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The magazine also features an article I wrote about the importance of mentoring and paying it forward to future generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/future-leaders2.png&quot; alt=&quot;future leader pic 1&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Your success in life lies not only with what you can ascertain for yourself, but the abundance of change, knowledge and advice you impart to the next generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is how we progress as a race. By thinking bigger than ourselves, by appreciating the importance of offering to someone younger what you potentially may have not had yourself, by leading them forward and nurturing their unwavering focus and passion to guide it into a place of unprecedented achievement.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flipsnack.com/FutureLeaders/future-leaders-2020-21.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Top 150 Future Leaders Magazine - 2020/21 Edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to Adenike Adenitire and the team at Powerlist Magazine for organising such an empowering celebration event this week, featuring the likes of: Femi Oguns, J.P. Morgan, Latham &amp;amp; Watkins and Royal Air Force (RAF).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My article entitled &lt;strong&gt;“Teach One to Reach One…“&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“In August 2017 I was nearing the beginning of my time at sixth-form, eager and keen to make an impact in this next phase of my life. My flourishing interest in physics at the time was the perfect catalyst for focus and provided a productive avenue to channel my efforts to learn and explore. I distinctively remember approaching my physics teacher excited about the prospect of joining the school Physics society, only to be told that one didn’t exist and never had. After a period of disappointment, I took it upon myself to reach back out to the teacher. “Would it be possible to launch my own society?”. At first, he was hesitant of its potential success, but he did agree it was possible if I put in the time, effort and consistency.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My aim with this society was to inspire younger students in the school to question the workings of the everyday world and far beyond into the depths of space and time. Why does time run at different speeds at different places? If our universe is infinite, does that mean there’s another version of you somewhere out there? What would happen if you fell into a black hole? What is our purpose in the universe and are we alone? It was questions like these that my committee and I would pose in open discussion following each of my weekly presentations about a historic scientific discovery. Watching the eyes of the younger students light up as they realised the wonderment of our universe, or finally cracked a concept they had been struggling with was truly rewarding. With a strong weekly attendance and several students being inspired to further pursue physics at a deeper level, this experience gave me my first taste of the potential success of reaching out to give.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since joining Oxford, I have participated in my old sixth form’s “Oxbridge Symposium” where I spoke as a guest. Following this I thought it would be brilliant to produce a YouTube video outlining advice for applying and demystifying misconceptions. Throughout this first year I have also been mentoring three current sixth form students in the journeys to Oxford, acting as the role model and guide I so desperately would have cherished whilst applying myself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is the importance of teaching and reaching out to younger students? Paying it forward. Your success in life lies not only with what you can ascertain for yourself, but the abundance of change, knowledge and advice you impart to the next generation. That is how we progress as a race. By thinking bigger than ourselves, by appreciating the importance of offering to someone younger what you potentially may have not had yourself, by leading them forward and nurturing their unwavering focus and passion to guide it into a place of unprecedented achievement.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These experiences have unlocked significant parts of my character and made me much more giving and driven to help. These past experiences have been truly rewarding and I now actively reach out to younger students as a personal mentor and Oxbridge application mentor; however, I hope my ability to advise will soon span over a vast array of areas of life.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to all the other Future Leaders selected this year!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Silence In The Age of Noise</title>
   <link href="https://jaredrichard.co.uk/book-reviews/2020/11/17/silence-in-the-age-of-noise/"/>
   <updated>2020-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://jaredrichard.co.uk/book-reviews/2020/11/17/silence-in-the-age-of-noise</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An exploration into the importance of silence in our daily lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/silence-cover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive-book&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Erling Kagge, A previous Cambridge Philosophy student turned explorer, speaks of his 50 day expedition across Antarctica… with a broken radio. He envelops us in the silence he experienced, and uses this as a powerful tool to convince us of the benefits it can have in each of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The modern day has killed our attention spans. With such easy access to our phones, laptops, the internet, music etc. we provide ourselves a quick route away from boredom. Seldom do we find ourselves sitting in complete silence by ourselves and just thinking. Whilst this may not seem detrimental, it hinders our ability to intensely concentrate, truly listen when others are speaking and also find inner peace. In a study by the universities of Harvard and Virginia, scientists left individuals in a room alone for 15 minutes without their phones, music and reading or writing material. The researchers took this a step further and wanted to see if the individuals would rather experience something unpleasant, such as receive an electric shock, than sit alone with their thoughts. According to the researchers, being alone with one’s own thoughts ‘was apparently so aversive that it drove many participants to self-administer an electric shock that they had earlier said they would pay to avoid’. One participant pushed the button 190 times. Whilst this experiment may seem extreme and the theme easy to brush off as just the way life is, there are a select few, Kagge and myself included, who wish to challenge this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do we change this and find silence in our busy fast-paced lives? Kagge says ‘You cannot wait for it to get quiet. Not in New York, nor anywhere else. You must create your own silence’. This can mean a 50 day expedition across the south pole, but it can also mean stopping at your desk, closing your eyes and slowly breathing in through your nose and out through your mouth. It can mean going on a walk and leaving your phone at home, it can also mean immersing yourself is such a passionate activity that you are fully present, ignoring regrets about the past and fear of the future. The overarching theme Kagge is trying to drive home in this book is we can derive more purpose and meaning from our lives by finding silence in the age of noise. By going inwards instead of trying to keep up with what is outwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The starry sky ‘is the truest friend in life, when you’ve first become acquainted ; it is ever there, it gives ever peace, ever reminds you that your restlessness, your doubt, your pains are passing trivialities. The universe is and will remain unshaken. Our opinions, our struggles, our sufferings are not so important and unique, when all is said and done.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Silence is more of an idea. A notion. The silence around us may contain a lot, but the most interesting kind of silence is the one that lies within. A silence which each of us must create. I no longer try to create absolute silence around me. The silence that I am after is the silence within.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘I believe it’s possible for everyone to discover this silence within themselves. It is there all the time, even when we are surrounded by constant noise. Deep down in the ocean, below the waves and ripples, you can find your internal silence. Standing in the shower, letting the water wash over your head, sitting in front of a crackling fire, swimming across a forest lake or taking a walk over a field: all these can be experiences of perfect stillness too. I love that.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quotes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world disappears when you go into it.
Martin Heidegger (Philosopher)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of humanity’s problems stem from man’s inability to sit quietly in a room alone
Blaise Pascal (Philosopher)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brain is wider than the sky
Emily Dickinson (Poet)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sva Marga: Follow your own path&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Tuesdays with Morrie</title>
   <link href="https://jaredrichard.co.uk/book-reviews/2020/11/10/tuesdays-with-morrie/"/>
   <updated>2020-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://jaredrichard.co.uk/book-reviews/2020/11/10/tuesdays-with-morrie</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Short story reflecting on the value of life as one of two best friends nears their death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tuesdays-cover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive-book&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tuesdays with Morrie” is a short book describing how Mitch Albom’s relationship with Morris Schwartz develops during his final 6 months battling the AlS disease. We are taken on a journey with these two characters as Morrie suffers through ALS aged 78, causing him to reflect on his life and the meaning of death, whilst imparting wisdom and advice to his younger friend Mitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mitch left high school a year early and soon found himself out of his depth in college, surrounded by older students. Baggy tracksuits, blaring music from his car and walking around with a cigarette in his mouth he describes were fronts for his feelings of fear in this new environment. Morrie on the other hand was a teacher like no other. Instead of pretending to be something he was not, he was as open as they come, filled with joy and happiness and strived to connect deeply with his students. It is this juxtaposition that drew Mitch and Morrie together in an unexpected friendship that would carry Mitch through his college years and to pursue an honorary thesis after following Morrie’s guidance. Graduation sadly saw Mitch and Morrie part ways, and although Mitch promised he would stay in touch, he never did. 16 years later Morrie was featured on the TV show ‘Nightline” due to his newfound disease and the impact it was having on his life. As luck would have it, Mitch happened to be watching and was instantly moved to reach out and rekindle their friendship in the last 6 months of life Morrie had left to offer. This is where their journey starts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recurring themes in this book are the importance of love, forgiveness, compassion, being present, finding meaning and giving to others. Morrie often is found quoting from his favourite author W.H. Auden “Love each other or perish”. I often do find myself very focussed on work, as did Mitch in this book; hence, it was interesting to read Morrie’s perspective on finding balance in life. Focussing more on offering to others, sharing stories and building your community. Take time to listen to your loved ones while they are still close, be present when someone is talking to you. Truly listen to what they are saying. You find meaning in your life by devoting yourself to loving others and your community and creating something that gives you a purpose. I think the most important message from this book is to take time to reflect. Reflect on your character, how you treat others, what you spend your time consuming, what are you adding to the world. Focus less on holding grudges or maintaining an ego. Forgive and look for the positives, love each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I give thanks to my friend Ella who recommended this book to me. It did move me and triggered a long period of self reflection regarding my relationships with family members and friends and how I can be a better human to others. I too would recommend this book as a must read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interesting passage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sometimes you cannot believe what you see, sometimes you have to believe what you feel. And if you are ever going to have other people trust you, you must feel that you can trust them, too – even when you’re in the dark, even when you’re falling.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting passage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In the South American rainforest, there is a tribe called the Desana, who see the world as a fixed quantity of energy that flows between all creatures. Every birth must therefore engender a death, and every death bring forth another birth. This way, the energy of the world remains complete. When they hunt for food, the Desana know that the animals they kill will leave a hol;e in the spiritual well. But that hole will be filled, they believe, by the souls of the Desana hunters when they die. Were there no men dying, there would be no birds or fish being born. I like this idea. Morrie likes it, too. The closer he gets to good-bye, the more he seems to feel we are all creatures in the same forest. What we take, we must replenish.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite quotes from the book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A teacher affects eternity, he can never tell where his influence stops.
Henry Adams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you learn how to die, you learn how to live.
Morris Schwartz&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fate succumbs many a species: one alone jeopardises itself.
W. H. Auden&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Olympus Investment Management</title>
   <link href="https://jaredrichard.co.uk/finance/2020/11/05/olympus-investment-management/"/>
   <updated>2020-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://jaredrichard.co.uk/finance/2020/11/05/olympus-investment-management</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Co-founded a student led investment fund with Nathan Walemba that implements quantitative research alongside rigorous fundamental analysis to actively invest in the financial markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://olympus-fund.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Olympus Investment Management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Rich Dad Poor Dad</title>
   <link href="https://jaredrichard.co.uk/book-reviews/2020/08/12/rich-dad-poor-dad/"/>
   <updated>2020-08-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>https://jaredrichard.co.uk/book-reviews/2020/08/12/rich-dad-poor-dad</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rich-dad-cover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive-book&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Can't Hurt Me</title>
   <link href="https://jaredrichard.co.uk/book-reviews/2020/08/05/cant-hurt-me/"/>
   <updated>2020-08-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>https://jaredrichard.co.uk/book-reviews/2020/08/05/cant-hurt-me</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cant-hurt-me-cover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive-book&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>As A Man Thinketh</title>
   <link href="https://jaredrichard.co.uk/book-reviews/2020/07/29/as-a-man-thinketh/"/>
   <updated>2020-07-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>https://jaredrichard.co.uk/book-reviews/2020/07/29/as-a-man-thinketh</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/as-a-man.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive-book&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Digital Minimalism</title>
   <link href="https://jaredrichard.co.uk/book-reviews/2020/07/16/digital-minimalism/"/>
   <updated>2020-07-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>https://jaredrichard.co.uk/book-reviews/2020/07/16/digital-minimalism</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/digital-minimalism-cover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive-book&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Oxford Alpha Fund Stock Pitch Competition</title>
   <link href="https://jaredrichard.co.uk/finance/2020/06/05/alpha-fund-stock-pitch/"/>
   <updated>2020-06-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>https://jaredrichard.co.uk/finance/2020/06/05/alpha-fund-stock-pitch</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stock Pitch for Lululemon as part of the Oxford Alpha Fund Stock Pitch Competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a stock pitch I created with Nathan Walemba, in which we recommend a buy for Lululemon Athletica Inc. over a 5 month period from June – November 2020. This stock pitch was also put forward as an entry for the Oxford Alpha Fund Stock Pitch Competition – June 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lululemon stock pitch – NJ Stocks&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Tips for applying to Oxford University</title>
   <link href="https://jaredrichard.co.uk/general/2020/05/27/tips-for-oxford/"/>
   <updated>2020-05-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>https://jaredrichard.co.uk/general/2020/05/27/tips-for-oxford</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/s6U0Ynqjyu0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Oxford Research Competition & HABS Aske Project - First Prize Winner</title>
   <link href="https://jaredrichard.co.uk/physics/2019/01/25/higgs-hunter-aske-project/"/>
   <updated>2019-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://jaredrichard.co.uk/physics/2019/01/25/higgs-hunter-aske-project</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At age 16, I completed a 6-month independent research project into the potential existence of an undiscovered fundamental particle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work, in conjunction with Oxford University and CERN, was completed alongside my A-level studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through rigorous analysis and finding substantial evidence for its existence, my research was awarded a Distinction, selected as a winner of the &lt;em&gt;Oxford Physics “Higgs Hunters” 2019 Research Competition&lt;/em&gt; and also won First Prize for the annual &lt;em&gt;Haberdashers’ Aske’s Research Project Competition&lt;/em&gt;, selected as 1st from over 150 entries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my thesis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My speech at the annual &lt;em&gt;Aske Project Celebration Assembly&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LaTdSEJ27x0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before presenting my project at the celebration assembly, I sat a viva examination with an external Physics professor to discuss the scope of my project. Below are his comments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aske-viva-comments.png&quot; alt=&quot;Viva Comments&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Final report on my project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aske-distinction.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Viva Comments&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This research was an extension of my submission for the Oxford Physics ‘Higgs Hunters’ competition. As a result of being selected as a winner, I was honoured to be invited to present my findings over a two day conference at Oxford. Here is a video of the event:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/E7JP_P9-jX0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photos of both events:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aske-project1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Viva Comments&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aske-project3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Viva Comments&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aske-project2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Viva Comments&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/higgs-hunter1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Viva Comments&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/higgs-hunter2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Viva Comments&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why Physics?</title>
   <link href="https://jaredrichard.co.uk/physics/2018/12/23/why-physics/"/>
   <updated>2018-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://jaredrichard.co.uk/physics/2018/12/23/why-physics</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I hated Physics. All through my time at school. This was up until early year 12 when by pure chance, my dad recommended I watch the film ‘Interstellar’ with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christopher Nolan’s interpretation of the blend between science and love instantly captivated me, and it was my first introduction to black holes, relativity, and time dilation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often take a step back and wonder, why are we all here? Tiny organisms in an ever-expanding infinite universe that harbours billions of galaxies, each with trillions of stars. A cosmic arena that contains a multitude of phenomena, spanning from the violent implosion of a dying star, to the innocent growth of a flower. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gargantua (Black Hole) – Interstellar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe the meaning of life is to find our why we have been placed here. We all too often find ourselves consumed by daily trivialities, we must focus on bigger questions. As Stephen Hawking once said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Look up at the stars, not down at your feet
&lt;em&gt;Stephen Hawking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently a Physics Undergraduate at the University of Oxford, with a deep interest in the subtleties physics shares with other aspects of life. Whether that be the quantum physics that powers all modern technology (e.g. the laptop I am typing this on), Quantitative Finance, Artificial Intelligence, Space Travel and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my life I hope to share this interest with others, particularly the younger generation. Our future lies in the stars, we must venture forth and explore.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
